# UNIVERSIDAD TECNICA FEDERICO SANTA MARIA

# SEBASTIÁN DUQUE RODRÍGUEZ

# *Electronics Engineer* +56 9 8133 4798

sebastian.duque@titulados.usm.cl

# PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Civil Electronic Engineer, Major in Computers, graduated from the Federico Santa María Technical University. Project Management Professional (PMP) certified. SAP certified. Diploma in Artificial Intelligence (PUC). RPAs (drone) Pilot. Advanced English. 13 years' experience in IT (as Project Manager and Programmer): projects and customers located in the USA, Europe, Latin America and India. Main skills: problem solving, teamwork and self-management. As a personal project: He has researched with drones, by developing and building a quadcopter containing a FPV system and an on-board computer with computer vision (AI) capabilities.

## **EDUCATION**

2003-2010

UNIVERSIDAD TÉCNICA FEDERICO SANTA MARÍA.

Civil Electronic Engineer, Major in Computers and Minor in Telecommunications.

## POSTGRADUATE DIPLOMAS

2021 PONTIFICIA UNIVERSIDAD CATÓLICA DE CHILE.

Artificial Intelligence Postgraduate Diploma.

2014

INSTITUTO PROFESIONAL CHILENO BRITÁNICO DE CULTURA.

Business English Postgraduate Diploma.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

2021 - Today

# SOLUTION ARCHITECT - PROJECT MANAGER - FTWO TECHNOLOGY SPA.

- Professional Services Project Manager: Document Automation and SAP Solutions.
- Designed new Solutions based on tools such as: SAP workbench, SQL, and Visual .NET.

**Key achievement**: Consolidated consultancy projects through Kofax, by managing and implementing a document automation project for DAK Americas (USA and Canada).

# 2017 - 2021

# PROJECT MANAGER / SAP SENIOR CONSULTANT - MILTIC INTELLIGENT SOLUTIONS SPA.

- Created Technical and Commercial proposals of SAP document automation solutions (MM, FI, SD, QM, PI/PO integrations) and ABAP customizations.
- Led research projects based on ML with TensorFlow and Pytorch.

# Key achievements:

- Led international project of Suppliers portal Ariba Network for AES Global, working with consultancy companies. The team was distributed across multiple countries (Argentina, USA, India).
- Developed SAP ABAP component that integrates using Process Orchestration SAP with the SII (Chile), for processing electronic invoices of AES GENER.

# 2010 - 2017 SAP / CAPTURE CONSULTANT - LEXMARK CHILE SPA.

- Implemented a document automation solution for the Accounts Payable Area of several companies such as: Tres Montes Lucchetti, ENAP, Grupo Q (El Salvador), TGestiona (Argentina).
- Estimated times and resources of Consultancy Projects and developing Statements of Work.
- Developed .NET customizations.
- Trained users on Lexmark's solutions.
- He was trained on SAP Solutions, in ReadSoft Lab, Germany.

# Key achievements:

Led Technical implementation of SAP Document automation solution for Belcorp – a multinational beauty corporation that has presence in more than 12 countries – for which he moved to Bogotá for two months, where the workshops were developed, and the main technical parts of the solution were discussed and analysed along with the customer (massive process of documents, electronic invoices of Colombia, Chile, Costa Rica, and Ecuador, among others.)

## **EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES**

2008-2009 Project Manager of the Robotics Centre at the Federico Santa María Technical University.

# **CERTIFICATES AND COURSES**

| 2023 | RPAs Pilot.   | DGAC.                        |
|------|---|------------------------------|
| 2023 | Advanced Drone Training Course.   | UMILES.                      |
| 2020 | Project Management with AGILE methodology - Ed. 9.                        | U. Complutense de<br>Madrid. |
| 2019 | PMP Certification Ed. 6.  | PMI.                         |
| 2018 | PMP Course.   | SCM Capacitaciones.          |
| 2014 | Business English Postgraduate Diploma.                                    | IP Chileno Británico.        |
| 2011 | Training on SAP Solutions.  | ReadSoft - Alemania.         |
| 2011 | Corfo English Program.  | IP Chileno Británico.        |
| 2010 | <b>SAP Certified</b> development associate - ABAP with SAP NetWeaver 7.0. | SAP.                         |

# HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

| Playing Sports | Tennis and Paddle.                                |
|----------------|---|
| Reading Books  | Magical realism, historical fiction, and history. |
| Technology     | Building and flying drones, AI researching.       |